片名  綠野仙蹤
近四十年來，這個故事給予年輕人的心靈
以可靠的幫助，時間也無法將其溫馨的
人生觀排除於風尚之外，為了回報
你們這些忠實於這個故事的人
…為了年輕人的心靈
…我們奉獻上這部影片
她沒跟來了，托托
She isn't coming yet, Toto.
她弄痛你了嗎？
Did she hurt you?
她試著那麼做，不是嗎？
She tried to, didn't she?
快點，我們去告訴亨利叔叔和艾姆嬸嬸
Come on. We'll go tell
Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
艾姆嬸嬸！
Aunt Em!
你聽聽看喀爾胥小姐對托托做的…
Listen to what Miss Gulch
did to Toto--
桃樂茜，拜託！我們正在算東西！
Dorothy, please!
We're counting!
- 但她打它…
- 現在別煩我們，甜心
-But she hit him--
-Don't bother us now, honey.
孵蛋器壞了，看來我們會損失許多小雞
The incubator's gone bad and we're
likely to lose a lot of our chicks.
可憐的小東西
That poor little thing.
但是喀爾胥小姐用耙打托托…
But Miss Gulch hit Toto with a rake...
…因為她說托托每天都追逐著
她那只壞脾氣的老貓！
...because she says he chases
her nasty old cat every day!
…70只，桃樂茜，拜託！
--seventy.
Dorothy, please!
但它沒有每天這樣
不過一星期做個兩三次罷了
But he doesn't do it every day!
Just once or twice a week.
而且它根本抓不到她的老貓
現在她說她會…
And he can't catch her old cat anyway.
Now she says she'll--
桃樂茜！我們正忙著啊
Dorothy! We're busy.
噢，好吧
Oh, all right.
- 她怎樣？
- 不要急
-How's she coming?
-Take it easy.
你壓到我的手指了！
You got my finger!
你為什麼不把你的手拿開？
Why don't you get your finger
out of the way?
- 你來了
- 就在我手指上！
-There you are.
-Right on my finger!
幸好不是你的頭！
Lucky it wasn't your head!
傑可，我要拿喀爾胥小姐怎麼辦？
就因為托托…
Zeke, what am l going to do about
Miss Gulch? Just because Toto--
聽著，甜心，我要去把豬趕進去
Listen, honey,
l got them hogs to get in.
你沒用腦筋
你可能認為你根本沒任何頭腦
You ain't using your head.
You'd think you didn't have any brains.
我腦筋好得很！
l have so got brains!
那你怎麼不用？
Why don't you use them?
別經過喀爾胥小姐的地方
Don't go by Miss Gulch's place.
那麼托托就不會跑進她的花園
而你也不會有麻煩了
Then Toto won't get in her garden,
and you won't get in no trouble.
噢，杭克，你根本沒在聽，算了吧
Oh, Hunk, you just
won't listen, that's all.
你知道你的頭腦可不是稻草做的
Well, your head ain't made
of straw, you know.
快進去，在我把你們當廉價賭本之前！
Get in there before l make
a dime bank out of you!
聽著，孩子…
Listen, kid...
…你想讓老喀爾胥那小母牛恐嚇你？
...are you gonna let that old Gulch
heifer try and buffalo you?
她並不是無所畏懼！
你要拿出點勇氣來
She ain't nothing to be afraid of.
Have a little courage.
我才不怕她
l'm not afraid of her.
下次她再口出惡言
走向她並且當面藐視她
Next time she squawks,
walk up to her and spit in her eye.
那正是我要做的
That's what l'd do.
幫幫我，傑可！把我弄出這裡！
Help me, Zeke!
Get me out of here!
救命！
Help!
- 你還好吧，桃樂茜？
- 是的，我沒事
-Are you all right, Dorothy?
-Yes, l'm all right.
我掉進去，而傑可…
l fell in and Zeke--
喔，傑可，你就跟我一樣害怕！
Why, Zeke, you're just
as scared as l am!
你會讓只小豬把你變成懦夫嗎？
You gonna let a little pig
make a coward out of you?
看看你…
Look at you--
看這是什麼聊天聚會啊
什麼時候才會將工作做完？
What's all this jabber-wapping
when there's work to be done?
我就知道三個農夫做一件工作
是成不了事的
l know three farm hands
that'll be out of a job!
桃樂茜剛才…
Dorothy was--
我看見你用粗劣手法修補那機器
黑克瑞
l saw you tinkering with
that contraption, Hickory.
- 你和杭克回去馬車那裡
- 好吧
-You and Hunk get back to that wagon.
-All right.
但有一天他們會為我立個雕像…
But someday they'll erect
a statue to me--
好了，現在別又開始為那擺姿勢了
Well, don't start posing for it now.
空著肚子無法工作！拿些小煎餅吧
Can't work on an empty stomach.
Have some crullers.
- 謝了，蓋爾夫人
- 只是油煎的
-Gosh, Mrs. Gale.
-Just fried.
你看，桃樂茜掉到這…
You see, Dorothy toppled into the--
桃樂茜不該到豬舍附近玩的！
lt's no place for Dorothy
around a pigsty!
喂餵那些豬
在它們擔心自己得了貧血之前！
Feed those hogs before they
worry themselves into anemia!
你知道喀爾胥小姐說
她準備怎麼對付託托嗎？
Do you know what Miss Gulch
said she was going to do to Toto?
- 她說她會…
- 別再胡思亂想了
-She said she'd--
-Stop imagining things.
你總是自尋煩惱
你只要在今天幫我們解決困難…
You're always in a fret over nothing.
You just help us out today...
…還有找一個你不會有麻煩的地方
...and find a place where
you won't get into any trouble.
一個沒有任何麻煩的地方
Someplace where there
isn't any trouble.
你認為真的有那樣的地方嗎，托托？
Do you suppose there is
such a place, Toto?
一定有
There must be.
那裡不是搭船或火車能到達的地方
lt's not a place you can get to
by a boat or a train.
那地方離這裡很遠
lt's far, far away.
月亮之後…
Behind the moon...
…雨水的另一邊…
...beyond the rain....
∮在彩虹之上∮
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮有個高高的地方∮
Way up high
∮有一處我曾聽說的樂土∮
There's a land that I heard of
∮在搖籃曲中∮
Once in a lullaby
∮在彩虹之上∮
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮天空湛藍∮
Skies are blue
∮只要你敢於夢想∮
And the dreams that you dare to dream
∮這兒美夢都會成真∮
Really do come true
∮有天我將對著星星許願∮
Someday I'll wish upon a star
∮並在高高的雲端醒來∮
And wake up where the clouds
are far behind me
∮一個煩惱都像檸檬糖般融化的地方∮
Where troubles melt like lemon drops
∮在煙囪頂上高高之處∮
Away above the chimney tops
∮就在那裡你將會…∮
That's where you'll...
∮…找到我∮
...find me
∮在彩虹之上∮
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮青鳥飛翔之處∮
Bluebirds fly
∮鳥兒們飛越彩虹∮
Birds fly Over the Rainbow
∮那麼為什麼…∮
Why then...
∮…噢，為什麼我不能？∮
...oh, why can't I?
∮如果快樂的小青鳥飛翔∮
If happy little bluebirds fly
∮在彩虹的那端∮
Beyond the rainbow
∮為什麼，噢，為什麼…∮
Why, oh, why...
∮…我不能？∮
...can't I?
蓋爾
Mr. Gale.
你好，喀爾胥小姐
Howdy, Miss Gulch.
我必須和你和你的太太談談桃樂茜
l want to see you and
your wife about Dorothy.
- 桃樂茜做了什麼？
- 她做了什麼？
-What has Dorothy done?
-What's she done?
我全身都好，除了我的腳被咬變跛之外
l'm all but lame from
the bite on my leg!
- 你是說她咬你？
- 不，是她的狗！
-You mean, she bit you?
-No, her dog!
她咬她的狗？
She bit her dog, eh?
不是
No.
那條狗是個威脅
我要捕捉它，以確定它被毀滅
That dog's a menace. l'm taking
him to make sure he's destroyed.
毀滅！托托？
Destroyed! Toto?
噢，你不能！你不會吧！
Oh, you can't! You mustn't!
艾姆嬸嬸！亨利叔叔！
你們不會讓她這麼做吧，會嗎？
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry!
You won't let her, will you?
當然我們不會
Of course we won't.
我會嗎，艾姆？
Will we, Em?
拜託，艾姆嬸嬸！
Please, Aunt Em!
托托根本不知道它做錯了什麼
Toto didn't know he was
doing anything wrong.
我才是應該被處罰的人
罰我上床並不准吃晚餐
l'm the one that ought to be punished.
Send me to bed without supper.
交出那隻狗，否則我會告你
讓你失去你的農場
Hand over that dog or l'll bring
a suit that'll take your farm!
狗咬人違反法律對人的保障！
The law protects folks
against dogs that bite!
要她把它綁起來如何？它很溫和的
How about if she ties him up?
He's gentle.
- 對仁慈的人來說，那就夠了
- 那要由警長來決定
-With gentle people, that is.
-That's for the sheriff to decide.
這命令允許我帶走它
除非你想違抗法律
This order allows me to take him.
Unless you want to go against the law.
我們不會違抗法律
我很遺憾托托必須被帶走
We can't go against the law.
l'm afraid Toto has to go.
現在你瞭解原因了
Now you're seeing reason.
我要它放在這裡好帶走
這樣它就無法攻擊我
Here's what l'm taking him in,
so he can't attack me again.
我不會讓你帶走它！
l won't let you take him!
你走開！
You go away!
我會親自咬你的！
l'll bite you myself!
你這邪惡的老巫婆！亨利叔叔
艾姆嬸嬸，別讓她帶走托托！
You wicked old witch! Uncle Henry,
Auntie Em, don't let her take Toto!
我有許可！把它給我！
l've got an order!
Let me have him!
把它放進籃子裡，亨利
Put him in the basket, Henry.
- 多明白事理！
- 不要，亨利叔叔
-The idea!
-Don't, Uncle Henry.
噢，托托！
Oh, Toto!
艾米拉·喀爾胥
就因為你擁有半個郡…
Almira Gulch, just because
you own half the county...
…並不代表你可以支配我們！
...doesn't mean you can
run the rest of us!
23年來我一直忍耐著
不想告訴你，我對你的看法
For 23 years l've been dying
to tell you what l thought of you!
而現在…
And now--
好吧，身為基督徒女子
我不能將那說出口！
Well, being a Christian woman,
l can't say it!
托托，親愛的！
Toto, darling!
我又得到你了！
l got you back!
你回來了！
You came back!
我真高興！
l'm so glad!
他們會馬上到這裡來抓你
They'll be coming back
for you in a minute.
我們必須離開！
We've got to get away!
我們得離家出走！
We've got to run away!
喔，喔，喔！過夜的訪客？
Well, well, well!
Houseguests, eh?
你會是怎樣的人呢？
And who might you be?
不，不，現在別告訴我！
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
讓我們瞧瞧
Let's see.
你正在喬裝旅行中
You're traveling in disguise.
不，不是那樣
No, that's not right.
你正要去拜訪某人
You're going on a visit.
不，我想那不對
No, l'm wrong.
你離家出走了
You're running away.
你怎麼猜出來的？
How did you guess?
馬勃爾教授從不用猜的，他就是知道！
Professor Marvel never guesses.
He knows!
現在，為什麼你會離家出走？
Now, why are you running away?
不，不，別告訴我
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
在家中他們不瞭解你
他們不知感激你
They don't understand you at home.
They don't appreciate you.
你想見識其它地方
大城市，大山，大海
You want to see other lands.
Big cities, big mountains, big oceans.
為什麼會這樣
好像你能讀出我的內心想法
Why, it's just like you could
read what was inside of me.
托托，那很不禮貌！
我們還沒被邀請呢
Toto, that's not polite!
We haven't been asked yet.
它是受歡迎的
He's perfectly welcome.
就像隻狗對待另隻狗般，哼？
As one dog to another, huh?
現在，我們說到哪了？
Here now, where were we...?
為什麼我們不能跟著你
去看看歐洲的君王們？
Why can't we go with you
and see the crowned heads of Europe?
你有認識的？噢，你是說那回事…
Do you know any?
Oh, you mean the thing....
沒先問過我的水晶之前
我是不會做任何事的
l never do anything without
consulting my crystal first.
我們進去吧，我們會…
Let's go inside here. We'll--
進來吧，我會做給你看的
Just come along. l'll show you.
這就對了，這裡
That's right. Here.
就坐在這裡
Sit right down here.
那就是它
That's it.
這是同樣血統，魔力，可靠的水晶…
This is the same genuine,
magic, authentic crystal...
…被歐塞裡斯及艾西斯神的祭司們
用於法老王之祭典日…
...used by the priests of lsis and
Osiris in the days of the Pharaohs...
…埃及艷後用來看見
凱撒及安東尼逼近的水晶
...in which Cleopatra saw the approach
of Julius Caesar and Marc Anthony.
諸如此類等等
And so on, and so on.
你現在最好閉上你的眼睛一下子…
Now, you'd better close your eyes,
my child, for a moment...
…為了能跟造物主協調一致
...in order to be better in tune
with the lnfinite.
我們若沒辦法接觸造物主的話
是無法完成這些事的
We can't do these things without
reaching out into the lnfinite.
好了，可以了
Yes, that's all right.
現在你可以睜開眼睛了
我們將凝視著水晶內部
Now you can open them.
We'll gaze into the crystal.
我看見的是什麼？
一座有尖木樁籬笆的房子…
What's this l see?
A house with a picket fence...
…還有一座有風向標的穀倉…
...and a barn with a weathervane...
…及一匹奔跑的馬
...of a running horse.
那是我們的農場！
That's our farm!
那裡有位女士
There's a woman.
她穿著件圓點花樣的連衣裙
她的表情看起來憂心忡忡的
She's wearing a polka-dot dress.
Her face is careworn.
那是艾姆嬸嬸
That's Aunt Em.
是的，她的名字是艾米麗
Yes, her name is Emily.
對，她在做什麼？
That's right. What's she doing?
嗯，我沒辦法看得很清楚
Well, l can't quite see.
為什麼？她正在哭！
Why, she's crying.
有人傷害了她
Someone has hurt her.
有人令她傷心
Someone has just about
broken her heart.
我？
Me?
喔，那是她所深愛的人
Well, it's someone she loves very much.
某個她非常慈愛對待的人
Someone she's been very kind to.
某個在生病時她會悉心照顧的人
Someone she's taken care of in sickness.
我有次得了麻疹
她片刻不離的待在我身邊
l had the measles once, and she stayed
right by me every minute.
現在她在做什麼？
What's she doing now?
好的，她正…
Yes, she's--
這是什麼？
What's this?
為什麼？她將手放在她的心上
Why, she's putting her hand
on her heart!
她正對著床掉眼淚！
She's dropping down on the bed!
哦，就這樣了！水晶球已經變暗了
Well, that's all.
The crystal's gone dark.
你不會認為她真的病了吧，你會嗎？
You don't suppose she could
really be sick, do you?
- 我必須馬上回家！
- 我還以為你要跟我走
-l've got to go home right away!
-l thought you were going with me.
不，我必須馬上回到她身邊
No, l have to get to her right away!
快點，托托！快點！
Come on, Toto! Come on!
再見，馬勃爾教授，真是謝謝你！
Goodbye, Professor Marvel.
And thanks a lot!
最好找個地方躲起來，斯勒韋斯特
有個風暴來襲了
Better get under cover, Sylvester.
A storm's blowing up.
用農民的話來形容就像個大漏斗
A whopper, to speak in the
vernacular of the peasantry.
可憐的小孩，我希望她能平安到家
Poor little kid.
l hope she gets home all right.
把那些馬鬆開！
Get them horses loose!
黑克瑞在哪裡？黑克瑞！
Where's Hickory? Hickory!
該死的！
Doggone it!
那是個龍捲風！那是個龍捲風！
lt's a twister! lt's a twister!
桃樂茜！
Dorothy!
每個人都進去防風地窖！
Everybody in the storm cellar!
亨利，我找不到桃樂茜！
她在外面，在暴風圈內！
Henry, l can't find Dorothy!
She's out in the storm!
我們現在無法去找她
We can't look for her now.
快點，進去防風地窖！快一點！
Come on, get in the cellar!
Hurry up!
艾姆嬸嬸！
Auntie Em!
亨利叔叔！
Uncle Henry!
我們一定是在龍捲風裡面！
We must be up inside the cyclone!
喀爾胥小姐！
Miss Gulch!
托托…
Toto...
…我感覺我們已經不在堪薩斯了
...l have a feeling we're not
in Kansas anymore.
我們一定已經飛越了彩虹！
We must be over the rainbow!
現在我知道我們真的不在堪薩斯了
Now l know we're not in Kansas.
你是個好巫婆或壞巫婆？
Are you a good witch or a bad witch?
誰，我嗎？
Who, me?
我根本不是巫婆
l'm not a witch at all.
我是桃樂茜·蓋爾，從堪薩斯來的
l'm Dorothy Gale, from Kansas.
它是不是巫婆？
ls that the witch?
誰，托托？托托是我的狗
Who, Toto? Toto's my dog.
我有點頭昏腦漲的！
蠻支金呼叫我，因為一個新巫婆…
l'm a little muddled. The Munchkins
called me because a new witch...
…剛把一座房子掉在東方壞巫婆身上
...just dropped a house on the
Wicked Witch of the East.
而那裡有座房子，還有你在這裡…
And there's the house,
and here you are...
…而那些就是東方壞巫婆留下的
...and that's all that's left
of the Wicked Witch of the East.
蠻支金想知道
你是好巫婆還是壞巫婆？
What the Munchkins want to know is,
are you a good witch or a bad witch?
但是我已經告訴過你
我根本不是巫婆
But l've already told you,
l'm not a witch at all.
巫婆都是又老又醜
Witches are old and ugly.
那是什麼？
What was that?
蠻支金們，他們正在笑
因為我就是個巫婆
The Munchkins. They're laughing
because l am a witch.
我叫葛琳達，是北方巫婆
l'm Glinda, the Witch of the North.
你是？
You are?
請原諒！
l beg your pardon!
但是我從未聽過有美麗的巫婆
But l've never heard
of a beautiful witch.
只有壞巫婆才是醜陋的
Only bad witches are ugly.
蠻支金們很高興…
The Munchkins are happy...
…因為你從東方壞巫婆手裡
解救了他們
...because you freed them from the
Wicked Witch of the East.
但如果你樂意的話
能告訴我「蠻支金」是什麼嗎？
But if you please,
what are Munchkins?
生活在這裡的小矮人
這裡是蠻支金國…
The little people who live here.
lt's Munchkinland...
…而你是他們的國家女英雄
...and you are their national heroine.
沒關係了，你們可以出來並謝謝她了
lt's all right.
You may all come out and thank her.
∮出來，出來吧，不管你們在哪裡∮
Come out, come out
Wherever you are
∮見見這位
從星星掉下來的年輕女士吧∮
And meet the young lady
Who fell from a star
∮她從天上掉下來
她從很遠的地方掉下來∮
She fell from the sky
She fell very far
∮還有堪薩斯，她說那是星星的名字∮
And Kansas, she says
Is the name of the star
∮堪薩斯，她說那是星星的名字∮
Kansas, she says
Is the name of the star
∮她為你們帶來了好消息∮
She brings you good news
∮或者你們還沒聽說？∮
Or haven't you heard?
∮當她從堪薩斯掉下來時∮
When she fell out of Kansas
∮一個奇跡發生了∮
A miracle occurred
∮其實沒有奇跡，只是就這樣發生了∮
It really was no miracle
What happened was just this
∮風開始轉變，房子被拋擲∮
The wind began to switch
The house to pitch
∮突然間絞鏈開始鬆脫∮
And suddenly the hinges
Started to unhitch
∮接著一個巫婆趕著去實現個願望∮
Just then the Witch
To satisfy an itch
∮坐在她的掃帚上飛過去∮
∮有人比著大拇指請求搭便車∮
Went flying on her broomstick
Thumbing for a hitch
∮還有，噢，然後發生的實在太多∮
And oh, what happened then was rich
∮房子被開始拋擲，廚房產生了裂縫∮
The house began to pitch
The kitchen took a slitch
∮它著陸在壞巫婆的水道中間∮
It landed on the Wicked Witch
In the middle of a ditch
∮對壞巫婆來說那可不是個好境遇∮
Which was not a healthy situation
For the Wicked Witch
∮房子被開始拋擲，廚房產生了裂縫∮
The house began to pitch
The kitchen took a slitch
∮它著陸在壞巫婆的水道中間∮
It landed on the Wicked Witch
In the middle of a ditch
∮對壞巫婆來說那可不是個好境遇∮
Which was not a healthy situation
For the Wicked Witch
∮誰開始在抽搐，而且縮成一小團∮
Who began to twitch
And was reduced to just a stitch
∮那曾經有個壞巫婆∮
Of what was once the Wicked Witch
∮我們要很甜蜜的謝謝你∮
We thank you very sweetly
∮為了你將它處理得這麼乾淨俐落∮
For doing it so neatly
∮你讓她死得永不超生∮
You've killed her so completely
∮我們要很甜蜜的謝謝你∮
That we thank you very sweetly
散播這快樂的消息吧！
邪惡的老巫婆終於死了！
Let the joyous news be spread!
The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
∮叮-咚！巫婆死了
哪個老巫婆？壞巫婆∮
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead
Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
∮叮-咚！壞巫婆已經死了∮
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
∮醒醒，你這貪睡鬼
擦亮你的眼睛，離開你的床∮
Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed
∮醒來吧，壞巫婆已經死了∮
Wake up, the Wicked Witch is dead
∮她去了小妖精去的地方
在下面，在下面，在下面∮
She's gone where the goblins go
Below, below, below
∮呦-呵！讓我們開懷並歡唱
並且搖響鈴聲∮
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing
And ring the bells out
∮叮-咚！這歡樂
在高處歡唱，在低處歡唱∮
Ding-Dong! The merry-o
Sing it high, sing it low
∮讓他們知道這壞巫婆死了∮
Let them know
The Wicked Witch is dead
∮身為蠻支金市市長∮
As mayor of the Munchkin City
∮在奧茲國土的郡城上∮
In the county of the Land of Oz
∮我以對待帝王般的熱誠來歡迎你∮
I welcome you most regally
∮但我們必須以法律上的方式證實它∮
But we've got to verify it legally
∮- 去目賭∮
∮- 去目賭？∮
-To see
-To see?
∮- 是否她∮
∮- 是否她？∮
-If she
-If she?
∮確實的，合規定的∮
Is morally, ethically
∮- 精神上，生理上∮
∮- 肯定地，絕對的∮
-Spiritually, physically
-Positively, absolutely
∮確鑿無疑地，真實的死了∮
Undeniably and reliably dead
∮身為驗屍官，我必須宣告那是事實∮
As coroner I must aver
∮我已經徹底的檢驗過她∮
I thoroughly examined her
∮而她不僅僅是死了∮
And she's not only merely dead
∮她是從內到外的死透了∮
She's really most sincerely dead
那麼這是獨立日…
Then this is a Day of lndependence...
…對所有蠻支金人及其子孫
...for all the Munchkins
and their descendants.
如果有的話！
if any!
是的，讓我們散播這快樂的消息吧！
這邪惡的老巫婆終於死了！
Yes, let the joyous news be spread.
The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
∮叮-咚！巫婆死了
哪個老巫婆？壞巫婆∮
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead
Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
∮叮-咚！壞巫婆已經死了∮
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
∮醒醒，你這貪睡鬼
擦亮你的眼睛，離開你的床∮
Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed
∮醒來吧，壞巫婆已經死了∮
Wake up
The Wicked Witch is dead
∮她去了小妖精去的地方
在下面，在下面，在下面∮
She's gone where the goblins go
Below, below, below
∮呦-呵！讓我們開懷並歡唱
並且搖響鈴聲∮
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing
And ring the bells out
∮叮-咚！這歡樂
在高處歡唱，在低處歡唱∮
Ding-Dong! The merry-o
Sing it high, sing it low
∮讓他們知道這壞巫婆死了∮
Let them know the Wicked Witch is dead
∮我們代表搖籃聯盟∮
We represent the Lullaby League
∮搖籃聯盟∮
The Lullaby League
∮以搖籃聯盟之名∮
And in the name of the Lullaby League
∮我們竭誠歡迎你到蠻之金國∮
We wish to welcome you
To Munchkinland
∮我們代表棒棒糖協會∮
We represent the Lollipop Guild
∮棒棒糖協會∮
The Lollipop Guild
∮以棒棒糖協會之名∮
And in the name of the Lollipop Guild
∮我們竭誠歡迎你到蠻之金國∮
We wish to welcome you
To Munchkinland
∮我們歡迎你到蠻之金國∮
We welcome you to Munchkinland
∮從今以後你將會名留青史∮
From now on you'll be history
∮- 你將會…∮
∮- 你將會名留青史∮
-You'll be his--
-You'll be history
∮我們將讚美你的名字∮
And we will glorify your name
∮- 你將被塑造成半身雕像∮
∮- 做成半身雕像∮
-You will be a bust
-Be a bust
∮- 做成半身雕像∮
∮- 在名人堂中∮
-Be a bust
-In the hall of fame
我以為你說過她死了
l thought you said she was dead.
死的她的姐姐，東方壞巫婆
That was her sister,
the Wicked Witch of the East.
這個是西方壞巫婆
她比另一個壞多了
This is the Wicked Witch of the West.
She's worse than the other one was.
誰殺了我姐姐？誰殺了東方巫婆？
Who killed my sister?
Who killed the Witch of the East?
是你嗎？
Was it you?
那是個意外，我並未存心殺死任何人
lt was an accident.
l didn't mean to kill anybody.
好吧，我的小美人
我也可以引發些意外的
Well, my little pretty,
l can cause accidents too!
- 你忘了紅寶石鞋嗎？
- 紅鞋，對！
-Aren't you forgetting the ruby slippers?
-The slippers. Yes!
紅鞋！
The slippers!
它們不見了！
They're gone!
那對紅寶石鞋！你對它們做了什麼？
The ruby slippers!
What have you done with them?
把它們還我，否則我會…
Give them back to me or l'll--
太遲了！它們在那，而且會留在那裡！
lt's too late! There they are,
and there they'll stay!
把我的紅鞋還我！
只有我知道如何使用它們
Give me back my slippers!
Only l know how to use them.
它們對你沒有用！把它們還我，還我！
They're of no use to you. Give them
back to me. Give them back!
穿著它們
Keep inside of them.
它們的魔力一定很強大
否則她不會這麼想要它們
Their magic must be powerful
or she wouldn't want them so badly.
別插手這事，葛琳達
要不然我連你一起修理！
Stay out of this, Glinda,
or l'll fix you as well!
噢，廢話！你在這裡根本沒法力
Oh, rubbish!
You have no power here.
走吧
在某人弄座房子也掉在你身上之前
Begone, before somebody
drops a house on you too.
很好！我會等待我的時機的
Very well. l'll bide my time.
而對你，我是真的無法在這裡
如我所願的對付你
And as for you, it's true l can't
attend to you here and now as l'd like.
但是試著別擋我的路！
But just try to stay out of my way!
只是試試！
Just try!
我會抓到你的，我的小美人…
l'll get you, my pretty...
…還有你的狗！
...and your little dog too!
沒事了，你們可以起來了，她走了！
lt's all right. You can get up.
She's gone!
沒關係了
lt's all right.
你們所有人都可以起來了
You can all get up.
這硫磺煙霧臭死了！
What a smell of sulfur!
我擔心你已經成了壞巫婆的敵人
l'm afraid you've made an enemy
of the Wicked Witch.
你們必須盡早離開奧茲國土
那你才能安心睡覺，我親愛的
The sooner you get out of Oz altogether,
the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
噢，我願付出任何東西來換取
讓我們離開奧茲國土
Oh, l'd give anything
to get out of Oz altogether.
但是哪條路能回到堪薩斯？
我可無法從原路回去
But which is the way back to Kansas?
l can't go the way l came.
是的，那倒是真的！
只有一個人可能知道…
No, that's true.
The only person who might know...
…那是偉大而神奇的奧茲大法師
...would be the great and wonderful
Wizard of Oz himself.
奧茲大法師？他是好的或是壞的？
The Wizard of Oz?
ls he good or is he wicked?
噢，非常的好，但是非常的神秘
Oh, very good, but very mysterious.
他居住在翡翠城，離這裡很遠的路程
He lives in the Emerald City,
a long journey from here.
你能用你的掃帚帶我跟著你去嗎？
Did you bring your broomstick with you?
不，恐怕不行
No, l'm afraid l didn't.
嗯，現在，你將必須徒步前去
Well, then, you'll have to walk.
蠻支金人會照顧你到蠻支金國邊界
The Munchkins will see you
to the border of Munchkinland.
還有記住讓紅鞋與你片刻不離…
And remember, never let those ruby
slippers off your feet for a moment...
…否則你將可要祈求西方壞巫婆
的憐憫了
...or you will be at the mercy
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
但是我要怎麼開始到翡翠城呢？
But how do l start for Emerald City?
從起點開始總是最好的
lt's always best
to start at the beginning.
你所要做的就是跟隨著黃磚路
And all you do is
follow the Yellow Brick Road.
- 但那會發生什麼，如果我…
- 只要跟隨著黃磚路
-But what happens if l--
-Just follow the Yellow Brick Road.
- 再見！
-Goodbye!
我的天！
My!
在這裡的人們來去都這麼匆忙！
People come and go so quickly here!
∮跟隨著黃磚路∮
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮跟隨著黃磚路？∮
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮跟隨著黃磚路？∮
∮跟隨著，跟隨著，跟隨著，跟隨著∮
∮跟隨著黃磚路∮
Follow, follow, follow, follow
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮跟隨著黃磚路∮
Follow the Yellow Brick
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮你要出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
You're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮你會發現他是天才中的天才
如果未曾有過這樣的天才∮
You'll find he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
∮如果未曾，如果未曾有過這樣的天才
那奧茲大法師就是一個，因為∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮因為，因為，因為，因為，因為∮
Because, because, because
Because, because
∮因為他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮你要出發去見大法師
那神奇的奧茲大法師∮
You're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
跟隨著黃磚路？
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
跟隨著黃…？
Follow the Yellow...?
現在我該走哪條路？
Now which way do we go?
抱歉！那條是非常好的路
Pardon me!
That way is a very nice way.
誰那麼說的？
Who said that?
別蠢了，托托！稻草人不會說話
Don't be silly, Toto.
Scarecrows don't talk.
走那條路也一樣讓人愉快
lt's pleasant down that way too.
真好笑，他剛才不是指著另一條路嗎？
That's funny.
Wasn't he pointing the other way?
當然，人們會走這兩條路的
Of course, people do go both ways.
喔，你真的說了些什麼，不是嗎？
Why, you did say something, didn't you?
你是故意那樣做的
還是你沒辦法做決定？
Are you doing that on purpose,
or can't you make up your mind?
那就是麻煩所在，我沒辦法做決定！
That's the trouble.
l can't make up my mind.
我沒得到個頭腦！
l haven't got a brain.
只有稻草
Only straw.
如果你沒頭腦，你怎麼能說話？
How can you talk if you
haven't got a brain?
我不知道
l don't know.
但是有些人不也是不用頭腦
就能說一大些廢話，不是嗎？
But some people without brains
do a lot of talking, don't they?
是的，我想你是對的
Yes, l guess you're right.
哦，我們還沒正式認識吧，對嗎？
Well, we haven't really
met properly, have we?
當然，沒有
Why, no.
你好嗎？
How do you do?
- 很好，謝謝你
- 我一點都不覺得好
-Very well, thank you.
-l'm not feeling at all well.
整天跟背後的這根柱子一起
一直卡在這裡真是使人厭煩
lt's very tedious being stuck up here
all day long with a pole up your back.
噢，親愛的，那一定很不舒服！
你不能下來嗎？
Oh, dear. That must be terribly
uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
下來？不行，你看，我…
嗯，我…
Down? No, you see, l'm--
Well, l'm--
喔，這裡，讓我來幫你
Well, here. Let me help you.
你真是好心，非常好心
That's very kind of you.
Very kind.
噢，親愛的，我沒看到…
Oh, dear. l don't see....
當然，關於做事我不是很機靈…
Of course, l'm not bright
about doing things...
…但是如果你將釘子折彎的話
也許我可以滑下去，並且…
...but if you'll just bend
the nail down, maybe l'll slip off and--
噢，是的！
Oh, yes!
這裡又有些從我身體裡跑出來了！
There goes some of me again!
那會弄痛你嗎？
Does it hurt you?
噢，不會！
我只要撿起它，再把它塞回去
l just keep picking it up
and putting it back in again.
我的天！自由的感覺真好！
My! lt's good to be free!
我嚇著你了嗎？
Did l scare you?
我只是以為你傷害到你自己
l just thought you hurt yourself.
我沒嚇著你？
l didn't scare you?
不，當然沒有
No, of course not.
我可不那麼認為
l didn't think so.
噗！趕快走開！噗！
Boo! Scat! Boo!
你看到沒？我連只烏鴉也嚇不了
You see?
l can't even scare a crow.
它們從附近飛來我的田里吃東西
還譏笑我的臉
They come from miles around just to eat
in my field and laugh in my face.
噢，我是個失敗者
因為我沒有個頭腦！
Oh, l'm a failure, because
l haven't got a brain!
如果你有個頭腦你會怎麼做？
What would you do
with a brain if you had one?
做？當然，如果我有個頭腦，我可能…
Do? Why, if l had a brain, l could--
∮我可能離開個幾小時，跟花兒呢喃∮
I could while away the hours
Conferring with the flowers
∮跟雨水交換意見∮
Consulting with the rain
∮當我搔搔我的頭，靈感便泉湧∮
And my head I'd be scratchin'
While my thoughts were busy hatchin'
∮只要我有個頭腦∮
If I Only Had a Brain
∮我會解開每一個謎題∮
∮為每一個陷入麻煩或痛苦的人∮
I'd unravel every riddle
For any individ'le
∮有思想，你就能思考
你可以成為另一個林肯∮
In trouble or in pain
∮只要你有個頭腦∮
With the thoughts you'd be thinkin'
You could be another Lincoln
∮噢，我能告訴你為什麼∮
If you only had a brain
Oh, I could tell you why
∮海洋會親近海岸∮
The ocean's near the shore
∮我可以思考以往從未想過的事情∮
I could think of things
I never thunk before
∮還有我會坐下來，並想得更多∮
And then I'd sit
And think some more
∮我將不會再一無所有
我的頭惱充滿了東西∮
I would not be just a nothin'
My head all full of stuffin'
∮我的心滿載著痛苦∮
My heart all full of pain
∮我會愉悅，跳舞
生命將是一首反覆的民謠∮
I would dance and be merry
Life would be a ding-a-derry
∮只要我有個頭腦∮
If I Only Had a Brain
好極了！
Wonderful!
如果我們在堪薩斯的稻草人
能那樣做…
if our scarecrow back in Kansas
could do that...
- …那烏鴉們會嚇成碎片！
- 它們會？
-...the crows would be scared to pieces!
-They would?
- 堪薩斯在哪裡？
- 那是我住的地方
-Where's Kansas?
-That's where l live.
我非常想回去哪裡！
我正要去翡翠城…
l want to get back there so badly,
l'm going to Emerald City...
…去請求奧茲大法師幫助我
...to get the Wizard of Oz to help me.
你正要去見一個大法師？
You're going to see a wizard?
你認為如果我去的話
大法師會給我頭腦嗎？
Do you think if l went,
this wizard would give me brains?
我不敢說
l couldn't say.
但即使他不能，你也不會比現在更糟
But even if he didn't, you'd be
no worse off than you are now.
- 對，那是真的
- 但也許你最好不要
-Yes, that's true.
-But maybe you better not.
我讓一個巫婆很生氣
也許會讓你惹上麻煩
l've got a witch mad at me,
and you might get into trouble.
巫婆？
Witch?
我不怕巫婆！我任何事都不怕！
l'm not afraid of a witch!
l'm not afraid of anything!
除了一跟點著了的火柴
Except a lighted match.
我不怪你
l don't blame you.
但是為了有機會取得頭腦的話
我寧願面對一整盒的火柴
But l'd face a whole box of them
for the chance of getting some brains.
我不會增添任何麻煩
因為我不必吃任何東西
l won't be any trouble,
because l don't eat a thing.
而且我也不會試著去操控事情
因為我不會思考
And l won't try to manage things,
because l can't think.
你願意帶我一起去嗎？
Won't you take me with you?
當然我願意！
Of course l will!
萬歲！我們出發去見大法師吧！
Hooray! We're off to see a wizard!
- 你出發得並不怎麼順利
- 我會試的！真的，我會！
-You're not starting out very well.
-l'll try! Really, l will!
- 到奧茲？
- 到奧茲！
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮你會發現他是天才中的天才
如果未曾有過這樣的天才∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
∮如果未曾，如果未曾有過這樣的天才
那奧茲大法師就是一個，因為∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮因為，因為，因為，因為，因為∮
Because, because, because
Because, because
∮因為他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
蘋果！
Apples!
噢，看啊！
Oh, look!
你以為你在幹嘛？
What do you think you're doing?
我們已經走了很長的一段路
而我感到很飢餓，還有…
We've been walking a long ways
and l was hungry and--
是你在說話嗎？
Did you say something?
- 她很餓！
-She was hungry!
喜歡有人跑來並從你身上拿走東西嗎？
How would like to have someone come
along and pick something off of you?
噢，哎呀！
Oh, dear!
我又忘了我不是在堪薩斯
l keep forgetting l'm not in Kansas.
過來，桃樂茜
Come along, Dorothy.
你不會要那些蘋果的
You don't want any of those apples.
你是在暗示我的蘋果
不是它們應有的模樣？
Are you hinting my apples aren't
what they ought to be?
你是在暗示我的蘋果
不是它們應有的模樣？
Oh, no! lt's just that she doesn't
like little green worms!
噢，你！
Oh, you!
我會讓你看怎樣得到蘋果的
l'll show you how to get apples.
萬歲！我想它辦到了！
Hooray! l guess that did it!
自個兒來吧
Help yourself.
當然，它是個人！
Why, it's a man!
用錫做的人！
A man made out of tin!
是的…！
Yes...!
看！
Look!
你說了什麼嗎？
Did you say something?
他說「油壺」
He said "oilcan."
什麼是油壺？
Oil can what?
油壺？
Oilcan?
在這裡
Here it is.
你希望從哪裡開始上油？
Where do you want to be oiled first?
他說從嘴巴
He said his mouth.
另一面
The other side.
謝天謝地！我又能講話了！
My goodness! l can talk again!
幫我的手臂上點油，拜託
肘部也上點
Oil my arms, please. Oil my elbows.
這裡
Here.
那會痛嗎？
Did that hurt?
不會，那感覺好極了
No, it feels wonderful.
我像這樣握著斧頭已經很久了
l've held that axe up for ages.
我的天！
Goodness!
你怎麼會搞成那樣子？
How did you ever get like this?
大約一年前…
About a year ago...
…我正在砍著樹…
...l was chopping that tree...
…突然間開始下起雨來
...when suddenly it began to rain.
就在砍到一半的時候，我就蛈矰F
And right in the middle of a chop,
l rusted solid.
從那時我就保持那樣直到現在
And l've been that way ever since.
你現在很完美
You're perfect now.
我的脖子，我的脖子
My neck. My neck.
完美？
Perfect?
敲敲我的胸膛
如果你認為我是完美的
Bang on my chest
if you think l'm perfect.
開始吧，敲敲它！
Go ahead, bang on it!
美極了！
Beautiful!
回音真棒！
What an echo!
它是空的
lt's empty.
錫匠忘了給我一顆心
The tinsmith forgot to give me a heart.
沒有心？
No heart?
沒有心
No heart.
所有都是空的
All hollow.
∮當一個人是個空水壺
他應該無所畏懼∮
When a man's an empty kettle
He should be on his mettle
∮而我卻悲傷莫名∮
And yet I'm torn apart
∮因為我認為
我可以成為人類∮
Just because I'm presumin'
That I could be kind of human
∮只要我有顆心∮
If I Only Had a Heart
∮會很溫柔，我會是文質彬彬
而且非常多愁善感的∮
I'd be tender, I'd be gentle
And awful sentimental
∮關於愛及藝術∮
Regarding love and art
∮我會與麻雀及邱比特為友∮
I'd be friends with the sparrows
And the boy who shoots the arrows
∮只要我有顆心∮
If I Only Had a Heart
∮我想像，一座陽台∮
Picture me
A balcony
∮上面，有個聲音低聲吟唱∮
Above, a voice sings low
∮你在哪裡，羅密歐？∮
Wherefore art thou, Romeo?
∮我聽到一陣心跳∮
I hear a beat
多甜蜜啊！
How sweet!
∮就讓那情緒表達出來吧
不管是妒忌還是摯愛∮
Just to register emotion
Jealousy, devotion
∮真正感受其中的滋味∮
And really feel the part
∮我將能保持青春及活力充沛
而且我會用拉鏈將它鎖藏起來∮
I could stay young and chipper
And I'd lock it with a zipper
∮只要我有顆心∮
If I Only Had a Heart
- 你還好吧？
- 我還有些不靈活
-Are you all right?
-l'm a little rusty yet.
噢，親愛的！
Oh, dear!
真是奇妙啊！
That was wonderful!
你知道…
You know...
…我們在想為什麼你不跟著我們…
...we were wondering why
you couldn't come with us...
…去跟大法師要個心
...to ask the Wizard for a heart.
如果當我們到達那裡
大法師卻不能給我一個心呢？
Suppose the Wizard wouldn't
give me one when we got there.
噢，但他會的！
Oh, but he will!
他一定要！
He must!
我們已經走了這麼遠的一段路
We've come such a long way already.
你稱那叫「遠」？
You call that long?
哎呀，你們才剛開始罷了！
Why, you've just begun!
一起幫這小女士，好嗎，我的好紳士？
Helping the little lady along,
are you, my fine gentlemen?
嗯，離她遠些…
Well, stay away from her...
…否則我會拿你來填床墊！
...or l'll stuff a mattress with you!
還有你！
And you!
我會用你當蜂窩！
l'll use you for a beehive!
接著，稻草人！要玩球嗎？
Here, scarecrow! Want to play ball?
Fire!
l'm burning! l'm burning!
我才不怕她
l'm not afraid of her.
我會照顧你直到見著大法師
不管我會不會得到個頭腦！
l'll see you get safely to the Wizard,
whether l get a brain or not!
拿我填床墊？！
Stuff a mattress with me!
我會照顧你直到到達大法師那裡
不管我會不會得到個心！
l'll see you reach the Wizard,
whether l get a heart or not.
當蜂窩！呸！
Beehive! Bah!
讓她試試用我來做蜂窩吧！
Let her try and make
a beehive out of me!
你們是任何人一生
所能擁有的最好的朋友
You're the best friends
anybody ever had.
那有趣的是
我覺得我已經認識你們一輩子了
And it's funny, but l feel as if
l've known you all the time.
- 但我之前沒可能見過你們，可能嗎？
- 我不知道怎麼會那樣
-But l couldn't have, could l?
-l don't see how.
當我被填充並縫製的時候
你並不在附近
You weren't around when l was
stuffed and sewn together.
而我生蚽蒂b那裡一段很長的時間
And l was standing over there
rusting for the longest time.
儘管如此，我希望我可以記得
Still, l wish l could remember.
但是我想那並沒有關係
But l guess it doesn't matter anyway.
我們現在彼此認識了
We know each other now.
- 對極了
- 是啊
-That's right.
-We do.
- 到奧茲？
- 到奧茲！
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我們聽說他是天才中的天才
如果未曾有過這樣的天才∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
∮如果未曾，如果未曾有過這樣的天才
那奧茲大法師就是一個，因為∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮因為，因為，因為，因為，因為∮
Because, because, because
Because, because
∮因為他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
我不喜歡這森林
l don't like this forest.
它陰暗而且令人毛骨悚然！
lt's dark and creepy!
當然，我不知道…
Of course, l don't know...
…但是我想在它變亮之前
它會越來越暗
...but l think it'll get darker
before it gets lighter.
你想我們會碰上什麼野獸嗎？
Do you suppose we'll meet
any wild animals?
可能會
We might.
有吃稻草的野獸嗎？
Animals that eat straw?
有些，但大部分的野獸是獅子
老虎和熊
Some, but mostly lions
and tigers and bears.
- 獅子！
- 還有老虎？
-Lions!
-And tigers?
還有熊！
And bears!
獅子，老虎和熊！噢，我的天！
Lions and tigers and bears!
Oh, my!
∮獅子，老虎和熊！∮
Lions and tigers and bears!
∮噢，我的天！∮
Oh, my!
∮獅子，老虎和熊！噢，我的天！∮
Lions and tigers and bears!
Oh, my!
∮獅子，老虎和熊！噢，我的天！∮
Lions and tigers and bears!
Oh, my!
把手臂抬起來！把手臂抬起來！
Put 'em up! Put 'em up!
你們誰先上？
Which one of you first?
我可以讓你們兩個一起來
如果你們希望
l'll fight you both together,
if you want.
我可以將一隻腳掌綁在背後跟你們打！
l'll fight you with
one paw tied behind my back!
我可以用一隻腳跟你們打！
l'll fight you on one foot!
我可以閉著眼睛跟你們打！
l'll fight you with my eyes closed!
拔出斧頭來對付我，哼？
Pulling an ax on me, eh?
偷襲我，哼？當然…
Sneaking up on me, eh? Why....
- 走開，別煩我們
- 噢，害怕了，哼？
-Go away and let us alone.
-Oh, scared, huh?
害怕，哼？
Afraid, huh?
你在罐頭裡能保持新鮮多久呢？
How long can you stay fresh
in that can?
快點，起來和戰鬥吧
你這顫抖的廢物堆積場
Come on, get up and fight,
you shivering junkyard.
抬起你的手，你這歪斜的乾草袋！
Put your hands up,
you lopsided bag of hay!
那是人身攻擊，獅子
That's getting personal, Lion.
是啊，起來並給它個教訓
Yes, get up and teach him a lesson.
對於教訓他，你有什麼問題？
What's wrong with you teaching him?
嗯，我很難瞭解他
Well, l hardly know him.
我一定會抓到你的，小東西！
l'll get you anyway, peewee!
你真是丟臉！
Shame on you!
你為什麼要那樣做？
我又沒有咬他
What did you do that for?
l didn't bite him.
沒有，但你試著去做
No, but you tried to.
找稻草人的碴就已經很糟糕了
不用再說去找只小狗的碴…
lt's bad enough picking on a straw man,
but picking on little dogs....
喔，你也不必跑來打我，不是嗎？
Well, you didn't have to go
and hit me, did you?
我的鼻子在流血嗎？
ls my nose bleeding?
當然沒有
Well, of course not.
我的天，都是你小題大作害的！
My goodness, what a fuss you're making!
當然，當你在附近找些
比你弱小的東西的碴…
Naturally, when you go around picking
on things weaker than you are....
你除了像個懦夫外，什麼都不是！
You're nothing but a big coward!
你是對的，我是個懦夫！
You're right, l am a coward!
我根本毫無勇氣
l haven't any courage at all.
我甚至會被自己嚇到！
l even scare myself!
看看我眼睛下的眼袋
Look at the circles under my eyes.
我已經有幾個星期沒睡覺了
l haven't slept in weeks.
難道你沒有試著數羊嗎？
Why don't you try counting sheep?
那沒有任何幫助，我怕它們
That doesn't do any good.
l'm afraid of them.
噢，那太糟了
Oh, that's too bad.
你想大法師也能幫它嗎？
You think the Wizard
could help him too?
我看不出為什麼不行
l don't see why not.
跟我們一起來吧
Come along with us.
我們正要去見大法師
去幫他得到個心
We're on our way to see the Wizard.
To get him a heart.
- 還有他的頭腦
- 他可以給你一些勇氣
-And him a brain.
-He could give you some courage.
你們跟只膽小的獅子在一起
會不會覺得丟臉？
Wouldn't you feel degraded to be seen
in the company of a cowardly lion?
我會
l would.
不，當然不會
No, of course not.
哇，你真是太好了
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
我的生命簡直無法讓人忍受下去了
My life has been simply unbearable.
哦，現在沒關係了
Well, it's all right now.
大法師將會解決每件事
The Wizard'll fix everything.
我已經忍受很久了
lt's been in me so long.
我將告訴你我的感受
l just gotta tell you how l feel.
快點！
Come on!
∮相信我，小姑娘，那真的很悲哀
當你天生膽小…∮
Yeah, it's sad, believe me, missy
When you're born to be a sissy
∮…沒有活力及激情∮
Without the vim and verve
∮但我可以展現我的英勇無畏∮
∮當一頭雄獅，而不是一隻老鼠∮
But I could show my prowess
Be a lion, not a mouse
∮只要我有勇氣∮
If I Only Had the Nerve
∮我恐怕無法否認
我只是頭漂亮的獅子∮
I'm afraid there's no denyin'
I'm just a dandy lion
∮我的命運不該如此∮
A fate I don't deserve
∮我該像暴風雪般勇猛
我該像蜥蜴般高貴∮
-I'd be brave as a blizzard
-I'd be gentle as a lizard
∮我該像沙囊般伶俐∮
I'd be clever as a gizzard
∮如果我要找的大法師
真的是個巫師∮
If the Wizard is a wizard
who will serve
∮那我就能得到一個頭腦∮
Then I'm sure to get a brain
∮- 一個心∮
∮- 一個家∮
-A heart
-A home
∮勇氣！∮
The nerve!
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我們聽說他是天才中的天才
如果未曾有過這樣的天才∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz
If ever a wiz there was
∮如果未曾，如果未曾有過這樣的天才
那奧茲大法師就是一個，因為∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮因為，因為，因為，因為，因為∮
Because, because, because
Because, because
∮因為他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮我們出發去見大法師
神奇的奧茲大法師∮
We're Off to See the Wizard
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
所以你們不想接受警告？
So you won't take warning, eh?
那對你們來說真是再糟不過了
All the worse for you, then!
我將會馬上對付你們！
l'll take care of you now
instead of later!
當我獲得那紅寶石鞋…
When l gain those ruby slippers...
…我將會變成奧茲國最偉大的人
...my power will be the greatest in Oz!
現在，我的美人們…
And now, my beauties...
…放點毒藥到裡頭，我想
...something with poison in it, l think.
加點毒藥到裡頭
With poison in it.
一定要能吸引眼睛的注意
以及聞起來讓人昏昏欲睡！
But attractive to the eye
and soothing to the smell!
罌粟
Poppies.
Poppies!
罌粟會讓他們睡著
Poppies will put them to sleep.
睡著…
Sleep....
現在他們將會睡著
Now they'll sleep.
那是翡翠城！
There's Emerald City!
噢，我們就要到了！終於！終於啊！
Oh, we're almost there!
At last! At last!
它真是美麗，不是嗎？
就跟我想的一樣
lt's beautiful, isn't it?
Just like l knew it would be.
居住在像那樣的地方
他一定真的是個神奇的大法師！
He really must be a wonderful wizard
to live in a city like that!
我們還等什麼？
What are we waiting for?
- 沒事！大家快點！
- 是呀，讓我們用跑的！
-Nothing! Let's hurry!
-Yes, let's run!
來吧！來吧！
Come on! Come on!
快點！快點！
Hurry! Hurry!
走啊！看！
Go! Look!
快點！
Come on!
看看這景色，真是美極了！
Look at the scenery. lt's wonderful!
翡翠城！
Emerald City!
發生了什麼事？
What's happening?
那是什麼？
What is it?
我好想睡覺，我再也跑不動了
l can't run anymore.
l'm so sleepy.
把手給我們，我們會拉著你
Give us your hands.
We'll pull you.
噢，不要，拜託
Oh, no, please.
我必須休息一下子
l have to rest for just a minute.
托托，托托在哪裡？
Toto. Where's Toto?
你現在不能休息，我們離那裡很近了
You can't rest now.
We're nearly there.
別哭！你會讓你自己再次生蛌滿I
Don't cry.
You'll rust yourself again!
仔細想想，打個瞌睡也不錯
Coming to think of it,
forty winks wouldn't be bad.
你不要也開始這樣！
Don't you start it too!
我們應該背著桃樂茜！
We ought to carry Dorothy!
我不認為我行，但我們可以試試
l don't think l could,
but we could try.
現在看著他！那太可怕了！
Now look at him!
lt's terrible!
過來，錫人，幫幫我
Here, Tin Man, help me.
這真是太可怕了！
This is terrible!
我無法移動她，連一寸都不能！
這是個咒語，一定是！
l can't budge her an inch!
This is a spell, this is!
那是壞巫婆做的！我們要怎麼辦？
lt's the Wicked Witch!
What'll we do?
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
這種時候像那樣大喊是沒有用的
lt's no use screaming
at a time like this.
沒有人會聽見的！救命！救命！
Nobody will hear you!
Help! Help!
救命！
Help!
下起雪來了！
lt's snowing!
不，那不是！
No, it isn't!
是的，那是！
Yes, it is!
也許那會有幫助！
Maybe that'll help!
噢，但那不可能有幫助！
Oh, but it couldn't help!
那有幫助！
lt does help!
桃樂茜，你醒來了！
Dorothy, you're waking up!
我們遇上了不尋常的天氣，不是嗎？
Unusual weather we're having,
ain't it?
看，他又蛈矰F！
Look. He's rusted again!
- 把油灌給我，快點！
- 這裡
-Give me the oilcan, quick!
-Here.
- 他蛈矰F
- 拿去
-He is rusted.
-Here.
- 這裡
- 快點！
-Here.
-Quick!
該死的！我詛咒她！
Curses! Curses!
總是有人幫助那女孩！
Somebody always helps that girl!
不管有沒有鞋子
我還是有足夠的力量來征服她
But shoes or no shoes,
l'm still great enough to conquer her.
還有把災難降給那些想阻止我的人
And woe to those who try to stop me!
讓我們離開這裡
Let's get out of here.
看啊！翡翠城更近了，還比之前更漂亮！
Look! Emerald City is closer
and prettier than ever!
∮你們已經脫離了森林∮
∮你們已經脫離了黑暗∮
You're out of the woods
You're out of the dark
∮你們已經脫離了夜晚∮
You're out of the night
∮步入了陽光之下∮
∮步入了光明之中∮
Step into the sun
Step into the light
∮筆直的前往這最輝煌的地方…∮
Keep straight ahead for
the most glorious place
∮…無論從在天上或地上來看∮
On the face of the earth
or the sky
∮屏住你們的呼吸∮
∮堅持你們的勇氣∮
Hold on to your breath
Hold on to your heart
∮緊握你們的期望∮
Hold on to your hope
∮向著大門行軍，命令它打開∮
March up to the gate
And bid it open
向著翡翠城而去，以閃電般的速度
To the Emerald City,
as fast as lightning!
∮你們已經脫離了森林∮
∮你們已經脫離了黑暗∮
You're out of the woods
You're out of the dark
∮你們已經脫離了夜晚∮
You're out of the night
∮步入了陽光之下∮
∮步入了光明之中∮
Step into the sun
Step into the light
∮向著大門行軍，命令它…∮
March up to the gate
And bid it...
∮…打開∮
...open
∮打開∮
Open
是誰搖的鈴？
Who rang that bell?
- 是我們！
- 你們沒看見嗎？
-We did!
-Can't you read?
- 看見什麼？
- 公告！
-Read what?
-The notice!
- 什麼公告？
- 那貼在門上的！
-What notice?
-lt's on the door!
清楚的就像鼻子在我臉上一樣！
As plain as the nose on my face!
「搖鈴是不合規定的
"Bell out of order.
請敲門」
Please knock."
喔！這比較合規定！
Well! That's more like it!
現在，說明你們的來意
Now, state your business.
我們想求見大法師！
We want to see the Wizard!
大法師？
The Wizard?
沒有人能見偉大的奧茲大法師！
But nobody can see the Great Oz!
從來沒人見過偉大的奧茲大法師！
Nobody's ever seen the Great Oz!
甚至連我也從未見過他！
Even l've never seen him!
哦，那你怎麼知道
那裡真的有這樣一個人？
Well, then, how do you know
there is one?
因為他是…
Because he's--
你們在浪費我的時間！
You're wasting my time!
噢，求你了，求你了，先生
Oh, please. Please, sir.
我一定得見到大法師
北方好巫婆叫我來的
l've got to see the Wizard.
The Good Witch of the North sent me.
證明給我看！
Prove it!
她穿著巫婆送給她的紅寶石鞋
She's wearing the ruby slippers
that she gave her.
所以她說的是真的！
So she is!
哦，想激怒我呀！
Well, bust my buttons!
為什麼你不一開始就這麼說？
Why didn't you say that
in the first place?
那狀況就完全不同了
That's a horse of a different color!
快進來！
Come on in!
馬車伕！馬車伕！
Cabby! Cabby!
那就是你們在找的東西！
我們負責帶你們到城裡任何地方！
Just what you're looking for!
Take you any place in the city, we does!
- 你會帶我們去見大法師嗎？
- 大法師？大法師嗎？
-Would you take us to see the Wizard?
-The Wizard? The Wizard?
是的，當然
但是我會先帶你們到一個…
Yes, of course. But first l'll
take you to a place...
…能讓你們梳洗的地方
...where you can tidy up.
噢，真是太謝謝你了
Oh, thank you so much!
我們走了這麼久的時間
覺得渾身髒兮兮的…
We've been gone such a long time,
and we feel so mess--
那是什麼品種的馬？
What kind of a horse is that?
- 我從沒見過那樣的馬！
- 是的，而且以後再也不會見到
-l've never seen a horse like that!
-No, and never will again.
這裡只有一個它，而它就是它
There's only one of him, and he's it.
它就是那不同顏色的馬(另一回事)
你曾經聽說過
He's the Horse of a Different Color
you've heard tell about.
∮哈，哈，哈！∮
∮呵，呵，呵！∮
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
∮還有幾個特啦啦∮
And a couple of tra-la-las
∮那是我們怎麼笑著過日子
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮嗶吉吉，嗶吉吉，嗶吉吉！
啁啾，啁啾，啁啾！∮
Bzz, bzz, bzz!
Chirp, chirp, chirp!
∮還有幾個特啦啦∮
And a couple of la-di-das
∮那是蟋蟀怎麼鳴叫終日
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how the crickets crick all day
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮我們十二點起床，一點開始上班∮
We get up at twelve
And start to work at one
∮一個鐘頭吃飯，兩點下班∮
Take an hour for lunch
And then at two we're done
∮快活好玩！∮
Jolly good fun!
∮哈，哈，哈！∮
∮呵，呵，呵！∮
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
∮還有幾個特啦啦∮
And a couple of tra-la-las
∮那是我們怎麼笑著過日子
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮哈，哈，哈！∮
∮呵，呵，呵！∮
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
∮哈，哈，哈，哈，哈！∮
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
∮那是我們怎麼笑著過日子
∮和一個…∮
That's how we laugh the day away
With a--
∮在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮用手輕拍，拍拍這裡∮
∮用手輕拍，拍拍哪裡∮
Pat, pat here
Pat, pat there
∮還有些全新的稻草∮
And a couple of brand-new straws
∮那是我們怎麼讓你保持年輕光彩
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how we keep you young and fair
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮磨擦，磨磨這裡∮
∮磨擦，磨磨哪裡∮
Rub, rub here
Rub, rub there
∮不管你是錫或銅∮
Whether you're tin or bronze
∮那是我們怎麼幫你維修良好
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how we keep you in repair
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮我們能用皺紋做出有酒窩的微笑∮
We can make a dimpled smile
Out of a frown
∮你們甚至能將我的眼睛染色
來搭配我的服裝嗎？∮
Can you even dye my eyes
To match my gown?
∮快活的老城鎮！∮
Jolly old town!
∮修剪，剪剪這裡∮
∮修剪，剪剪哪裡∮
Clip, clip here
Clip, clip there
∮我們送上最堅硬的爪子∮
We give the roughest claws
∮那無疑是良好教養的外貌
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That certain air of savoir-faire
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我們怎麼笑著過日子
在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我們怎麼笑著過日子
∮和一個哈，哈，哈…∮
That's how we laugh the day away
With a ha-ha-ha
∮在這歡樂的古老奧茲樂土∮
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
她是誰？她是誰？
Who's her? Who's her?
那是巫婆！
lt's the witch!
她跟蹤我們到這裡！
She's followed us here!
「投降吧，桃樂茜」
"Surrender, Dorothy."
桃樂茜？誰是桃樂茜？
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
- 大法師會解釋它！
- 到大法師那兒吧！
-The Wizard will explain it!
-To the Wizard!
噢，親愛的！我們應該怎麼做？
Oh, dear!
Whatever shall we do?
如果我們想見到大法師
最好動作快點！
We better hurry if we're
gonna see the Wizard!
過來！過來，過來！一切都很正常
Here! Here, here!
Everything is all right.
現在停下來，只要…
Stop that now, just--
沒事的！一切都沒事！
lt's all right!
Everything is all right!
偉大有力的大法師
已經完全控制住這些事了
The Great and Powerful Oz has got
matters well in hand.
我希望
l hope.
所以你們全部回家吧！
沒什麼好擔心的！
So you can all go home!
There's nothing to worry about!
離開這裡，馬上離開！回家去
Get out of here. Now go on!
Go on home.
回家去
Go home.
我們要馬上見大法師！
我們全部的四個人
We want to see the Wizard right away.
All four of us.
命令是，沒有人能見大法師！
沒有人，絕對不允許！
Orders are, nobody can see the Great Oz!
Not nobody, not nohow!
拜託！那非常重要！
But, please! lt's very important.
我得到的不變的命令
只能在重大典禮
l got a permanent
just for the occasion.
沒有任何人能見他，絕對不允許！
Not nobody, not nohow!
但她是桃樂茜！
But she's Dorothy!
巫婆的桃樂茜？
The witch's Dorothy?
好吧，那就不一樣了
Well, that makes a difference.
在這裡等著，我會馬上通知你們
Just wait here.
l'll announce you at once.
你們聽到嗎？他會馬上通知我們
Did you hear that?
He'll announce us at once.
- 我感到像已得到我的頭腦一樣
- 我簡直像已聽到我的心在跳著
-l've as good as got my brain.
-l can fairly hear my heart beating.
我將會在家吃著晚餐
l'll be home for supper.
再過一個小時，我將變成森林之王
ln another hour,
l'll be king of the forest.
國王萬歲！
Long live the king!
∮如果我是森林之王∮
If I Were King of the Forest
∮不是皇后∮
Not queen
∮不是侯爵∮
Not duke
∮不是王子∮
Not prince
∮我的森林帝袍∮
My regal robes of the forest
∮會是以綢緞製成∮
Would be satin
∮不是棉布∮
Not cotton
∮不是印花棉布∮
Not chintz
∮我將統治每件事
不論是飛禽或走獸∮
I'd command each thing
Be it fish or fowl
∮用聲低吼指揮！∮
With a woof!
∮用一聲低吼！∮
And a woof!
∮還有一種皇家的咆哮！∮
And a royal growl
∮當我的鞋跟喀嚓響起
所有的樹將會下跪∮
As I'd click my heel
All the trees would kneel
∮所有的山都將鞠躬∮
∮雄獸們都將卑躬頭叩頭∮
And the mountains bow
And the bulls kowtow
∮還有麻雀將會振翅高飛∮
And the sparrow would take wing
∮如果我∮
If I
∮如果我是個王∮
If I were king
∮每隻兔子將對我顯露敬畏之情∮
Each rabbit would show respect to me
∮花栗鼠們將對著我下跪∮
The chipmunks genuflect to me
∮雖然我的尾巴會鞭打處罰∮
Though my tail would lash
∮我仍會顯示∮
I would show compash
∮對我臣民的憐憫之心∮
For every underling
∮如果我∮
If I
∮如果我是個王∮
If I were king
∮就是個王∮
Just king
∮所有我所俯視之物的君王∮
Monarch of all I survey
∮君王∮
Monarch
∮對所有我所俯視之物∮
Of all I survey
如果你是個王
你將不再懼怕任何事？
if you were king,
you wouldn't be afraid of anything?
沒有，絕對沒有！
Not nobody, not nohow!
- 即使是頭犀牛？
- 不可能！
-Not even a rhinoceros?
-lmposserous!
- 那河馬行嗎？
- 我會從頭到底痛毆他一頓
-How about a hippopotamus?
-l'd trash him from top to "bottom-us."
- 假設你碰見一頭大象呢？
- 我會把它打包到玻璃紙裡
-Supposing you met an elephant?
-l'd wrap him up in "cello-phant" !
- 那如果是雷龍呢？
- 我會讓它知道誰才是森林之王！
-What if it were a brontosaurus?
-l'd show him who's king of the forest!
- 怎麼樣？
- 什麼怎麼樣？
-How?
勇氣啊！
Courage!
什麼讓奴隸蛻化成國王？勇氣！
What makes a king out of a slave?
Courage!
什麼讓桅桿上的旗幟飛揚？勇氣！
What makes the flag on the mast to wave?
Courage!
什麼讓大象用象牙發起攻擊…
What makes the elephant
charge his tusk...
…在朦朧不清的霧裡
或在幽暗的薄暮中？
...in the misty mist
or the dusky dusk?
什麼讓麝鼠敢於捍衛它的麝香？勇氣！
What makes the muskrat guard his musk?
Courage!
什麼讓斯芬克斯(人面獅身像)
成為七大奇跡？勇氣！
What makes the sphinx
the Seventh Wonder? Courage!
什麼讓黎明像雷聲般砰然乍現？
What makes the dawn come up
like thunder?
勇氣！
Courage!
什麼讓霍屯督人這麼熱情？
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
什麼把猴子放在杏樹中？
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
他們擁有什麼是我沒有的？
What have they got that l ain't got?
- 勇氣！
- 你們能再說一遍嗎？
-Courage!
-You can say that again.
大法師叫你們離開！
The Wizard says go away!
離開？
Go away?
看來我們遠道而來卻一無所得
Looks like we came a long way
for nothing.
而且我還曾如此快樂
And l was so happy.
我還以為我已經邁向回家的路途了
l thought l was on my way home.
別哭，我們會讓你見到大法師的
Don't cry.
We're gonna get you to the Wizard.
我們一定會
We certainly are.
艾姆嬸嬸以前對我那麼好…
Auntie Em was so good to me...
…而我從不知感激
...and l never appreciated it.
還離家出走，傷了她的心
Running away and hurting her feelings.
馬勃爾教授說她病了
Professor Marvel said she was sick.
她可能將要死去…
She may be dying...
…而那全是我的錯
...and it's all my fault.
我將永遠不會原諒自己
l'll never forgive myself.
永遠，永遠，永遠
Never, never, never.
請別再哭了
Please don't cry anymore.
我會想個辦法讓你進到大法師那裡
l'll get you into the Wizard somehow.
來吧，我自己也曾經經歷過一次
像艾姆嬸嬸這樣的事情
Come on.
l had an Aunt Em myself once.
等一下，夥伴們
Wait a minute, fellas.
我剛在想，我似乎不這麼想見大法師
l was just thinking, l don't want
to see the Wizard this much.
我最好還是在外面等你們
l better wait for you outside.
- 又怎麼了？
- 他只不過又害怕了
-What's the matter?
-He's just scared again.
難道你不知道大法師會給你勇氣？
Don't you know the Wizard will
give you courage?
我太害怕了
所以不敢開口要求他給我勇氣
l'd be too scared to ask him for it.
好吧，那麼我會幫你要求的
Well, then, we'll ask him for you.
我寧願待在外頭
l'd sooner wait outside.
為什麼？為什麼？
Why? Why?
因為我還是感到害怕！
Because l'm still scared!
- 發生什麼事？
- 有人拉著我的尾巴
-What happened?
-Somebody pulled my tail.
你自己拉的啦
You did it yourself.
過來
Here.
走吧
Come on.
走向前來！
Come forward!
當它結束時再告訴我！
Tell me when it's over!
看看那個，看看那個！
Look at that. Look at that!
我要回家！
l wanna go home!
我是奧茲…
l am Oz...
…偉大又強大！
...the Great and Powerful!
你們是什麼人？
Who are you?
若是讓您喜歡…
if you please...
…我是桃樂茜…
...l am Dorothy...
…卑微而溫順的
...the small and meek.
我們來請求您…
We've come to ask you--
安靜！
Silence!
噢！我的老天！
Oh! Jiminy crickets!
偉大又強大的奧茲…
The Great and Powerful Oz...
…知道你們為什麼而來
...knows why you have come.
走向前…
Step forward...
…錫人！
...Tin Man!
你膽敢到這裡向我要求顆心，是嗎？
You dare to come to me
for a heart, do you?
你這叮叮噹噹作響的…
You clinking, clanking, clattering...
…廢棄舊物組合的廢物！
...collection of caliginous junk!
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
是的，閣下
Yes, Your Honor.
你知道…
You see...
…不久之前，我們沿著黃磚道…
...a while back, we were walking down
the Yellow Brick Road--
住嘴！
Quiet!
還有你，稻草人…
And you, Scarecrow...
…厚顏無恥的來求取一個腦…
...have the effrontery
to ask for a brain...
…你這一大包牛飼料！
...you billowing bale of bovine fodder!
是的，閣下，我是說，尊貴的閣下
Yes, Your Honor.
l mean, Your Excellency.
我是說，尊貴的大法師！
l mean, Your Wizardry!
夠了！
Enough!
還有你，獅子！
And you, Lion!
喔？
Well?
你應該為你自己感到羞愧…
You ought to be ashamed of yourself...
…當他來請求你的幫助時
把他嚇成那樣子！
...frightening him like that
when he came to you for help!
安靜…
Silence...
…傲慢的傢伙！
...whippersnapper!
仁慈的奧茲有意願准許你們的請求…
The beneficent Oz has every intention
of granting your requests.
什麼？他說了什麼？
What's that? What'd he say?
他說了什麼？
What'd he say?
但首先，你們必須證明你們值得…
But first, you must prove
yourselves worthy...
…完成一件小事來證明
...by performing a very small task.
將西方巫婆的掃帚帶來給我
Bring me the broomstick
of the Witch of the West.
但為了取得掃帚，我們將必須殺了她
But if we do that,
we'll have to kill her to get it.
帶給我她的掃帚…
Bring me her broomstick...
…而我將准許你們的請求
...and l'll grant your requests.
現在離開吧！
Now go!
但要是她先殺了我們呢？
But what if she kills us first?
我說「離開」！
l said go!
「假如我是你，我會回頭」
"l'd turn back if l were you."
我相信這裡到處都是幽靈
l believe there's spooks around here.
那太荒謬了！
That's ridiculous!
幽靈！那太愚蠢了
Spooks! That's silly.
你不相信有幽靈？
Don't you believe in spooks?
不，當然，只有…
No. Why, only--
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
我真的相信有幽靈！
l do believe in spooks.
我相信，我相信，我相信，我相信
l do, l do, l do, l do.
我真的相信有幽靈
我相信，我相信，我相信，我相信！
l do believe in spooks.
l do, l do, l do, l do, l do!
在我消滅你們之前
你會寧願去相信比那更多的東西
You'll believe in more than that
before l'm finished with you.
帶你的軍隊去將那女孩和她的狗
抓來給我
Take your army and bring me
that girl and her dog.
其他人就隨你高興怎麼處置
但是我要她活著
Do what you like with the others,
but l want her alive.
他們不會給你惹麻煩的
我可以向你保證
They'll give you no trouble.
l promise you that.
我會讓些小蟲當先鋒，將他們解決掉
l've sent a little insect on ahead
to take the fight out of them.
要特別當心那紅寶石鞋
那是我最想到的東西
Take special care of those slippers.
l want those most of all.
現在，飛吧！飛吧！
Now, fly! Fly!
將女孩和她的紅寶石鞋帶來給我
Bring me that girl and her slippers!
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
馬上滾開！
Go away now!
托托！托托！救命！
Toto! Toto! Help!
救命！救命！救命！
Help! Help! Help!
你怎麼了？
What happened to you?
他們把我的腳扯下丟到那裡！
They tore my legs off
and threw them over there!
然後他們又拿走我的胸膛丟到那裡！
Then they took my chest
and threw it over there!
你被丟的到處都是！
That's you all over.
他們確實將填充物從你身體扯出來
They sure knocked
the stuffings out of you.
別呆站在那裡！將我組合起來
我們必須去找桃樂茜！
Don't stand there. Put me together.
We've got to find Dorothy!
嗯，讓我瞧瞧…
Now, let's see....
多麼可愛的小狗啊
What a nice little dog.
還有你，我親愛的
And you, my dear.
多麼意外的榮幸啊
What an unexpected pleasure.
在我孤獨的時候來拜訪我
你真是體貼啊
lt's so kind of you to visit me
in my loneliness.
你想對我的狗怎麼樣？把它還我！
What are you gonna do with my dog?
Give him back!
別太著急了，我的小美人
All in good time, my little pretty.
別太著急了
All in good time.
請你把狗還我
Please give me back my dog.
當然，當然…
Certainly, certainly...
…只要你把紅寶石鞋給我
...when you give me those slippers.
但好巫婆告訴過我不能這麼做
But the Good Witch told me not to.
那好吧
Very well.
把籃子丟到河裡
Throw that basket in the river.
不要！你可以拿走你的舊鞋子
但是把托托還給我！
No! You can have your old slippers,
but give me back Toto!
那就對了，小女孩
That's a good little girl.
我知道你很明白事理的！
l knew you'd see reason!
我很抱歉！我無法辦不到
我是否仍能要回我的狗呢？
l'm sorry! l didn't do it.
Can l still have my dog?
不！我真是傻瓜，我應該要記得…
No! Fool that l am,
l should have remembered...
…這鞋子永遠無法脫下來…
...those slippers will
never come off...
…只要你還活著
...as long as you're alive.
但是那並不是我所困擾的
而是應該怎麼做這件事
But that's not what's worrying me.
lt's how to do it.
這些事必須很巧妙地完成…
These things must be done delicately...
…否則你會被咒語所傷害
...or you hurt the spell.
- 跑，托托，快跑！
- 抓住它，你這笨蛋！
-Run, Toto, run!
-Catch him, you fool!
快跑，托托，快跑！
Run, Toto, run!
它跑掉了！它跑掉了！
He got away! He got away!
我不知道你們哪個應得多些！
Which is more than you will!
詛咒，你和你的狗！
Drat, you and your dog!
你給我帶來的麻煩遠大於你的價值
You've been more trouble to me
than you're worth.
但是現在，那很快就會結束了！
But it'll soon be over now!
你看見這沒？
Do you see that?
這就是你還能活著的時間
That's how much longer
you've got to be alive.
而那不會太久的，我的小美人
那不會太久的！
And it isn't long, my pretty.
lt isn't long!
我可不能等一輩子才拿到鞋子！
l can't wait forever
to get those shoes!
我很害怕
l'm frightened.
我很害怕，艾姆嬸嬸！我很害怕
l'm frightened, Auntie Em!
l'm frightened.
你在哪裡呢？
Where are you?
是我，那是艾姆嬸嬸
lt's me. lt's Auntie Em.
我們正在找你，你在哪裡呢？
We're trying to find you.
Where are you?
我在奧茲這裡，艾姆嬸嬸
l'm here in Oz, Auntie Em.
我被關在巫婆的城堡裡…
l'm locked up in the Witch's castle...
…而我正在想辦法回家找你
艾姆嬸嬸！
...and l'm trying to get home to you,
Auntie Em!
噢，艾姆嬸嬸，別離開！
Oh, Auntie Em, don't go away!
我很害怕！
l'm frightened!
回來！回來！
Come back! Come back!
「艾姆嬸嬸，艾姆嬸嬸！回來！」
"Auntie Em, Auntie Em! Come back!"
我會給你艾姆嬸嬸，我的美人！
l'll give you Auntie Em, my pretty!
看！托托在那裡！
Look! There's Toto!
它從哪裡來的？
Where'd he come from?
當然，難道你不明白？
Why, don't you see?
它來帶我們去找桃樂茜
He's come to take us to Dorothy.
快點，夥伴們！
Come on, fellas!
我希望我的力量能夠維持下去
l hope my strength holds out.
我希望你的尾巴夠強韌
l hope your tail holds out.
那是什麼？
What's that?
那是壞巫婆的城堡！
That's the castle of the Wicked Witch!
- 桃樂茜在這可怕的城堡裡？
- 我痛恨她在裡面的想法
-Dorothy's in that awful place?
-l hate to think of her in there.
- 我們必須救她出來
- 現在別哭
-We've got to get her out.
-Don't cry now.
我們沒帶著油壺
而你發出的嘎吱聲好像蠻需要它的
We haven't got the oilcan, and you've
been squeaking enough as it is.
他們是誰？他們是誰？
Who's them? Who's them?
- 我有個計劃能進去
- 好極了，他有計劃了
-l've got a plan how to get in there.
-Fine. He's got a plan.
- 你必須帶領我們
- 對啊
-And you're gonna lead us.
-Yeah.
- 我？
- 是的，你
-Me?
-Yes, you.
- 我要從那裡救她出來？
- 是啊
-l gotta get her out of there?
-That's right.
好吧，為了桃樂茜我會去那裡
All right, l'll go in there
for Dorothy.
不管有沒有壞巫婆…
Wicked Witch or no Wicked Witch...
…不管有沒有警衛
我都會把他們撕成碎片
...guards or no guards,
l'll tear them apart.
也許我沒辦法活著出來
但我還是會去那裡
l may not come out alive,
but l'm going in there.
- 我只要求你們做一件事
- 什麼事？
-There's only one thing l want you to do.
-What's that?
當我失去知覺時跟我說話
Talk me out of it.
- 不，你別！
- 噢，不要
-No, you don't!
-Oh, no.
- 嗯，等等
- 上！
-Now, wait a minute.
-Up!
來吧，我想到另外一個主意了
Come on, l've got another idea.
你想的主意會受到歡迎嗎
像順道拜訪之類的？
Do you think it would be polite,
dropping in like this?
我們現在要去哪裡？
Where do we go now?
那裡！
There!
等等！我們最好肯定一下
桃樂茜，你在那裡嗎？
Wait! We better make sure.
Dorothy, are you in there?
是我們！
lt's us!
是的！
Yes!
是我！巫婆將我關在裡面！
lt's me! She's locked me in!
我們要救她出來！打開這門！
We gotta get her out! Open the door!
噢，快點！請快點！
Oh, hurry! Please hurry!
沙漏快要漏完了！
The hourglass is almost empty!
往後站！
Stand back!
我就知道你們會來！我就知道你們會！
l knew you'd come!
l knew you would!
快點，我們快沒時間了！
Hurry, we've got no time to lose!
這麼快就要走了？
Going so soon?
我可不是這麼聽說的
l wouldn't hear of it.
當然，我的小宴會才剛要開始
Why, my little party's just beginning.
我們被設計了，像抓老鼠的…陷阱！
Trapped.
Trapped like mice...rats!
對極了，別馬上傷害他們
That's right.
Don't hurt them right away.
我們要讓他們先稍微的考慮一下
We'll let them think about it
a little first.
抓住他們！抓住他們！
Seize them! Seize them!
阻止他們，你們這些笨蛋！
Stop them, you fools!
抓住他們！抓住他們！
Seize them! Seize them!
他們往那裡去了！
現在我們會逮到他們的！
There they go! Now we've got them!
你們一半走這條路，你們走那條路
Half you go this way,
half you go that way.
快點！快點！
Hurry! Hurry!
現在我們要往哪裡走？
Where do we go now?
這條路，快點！
This way. Come on!
回去！回去！
Back! Back!
很好！
Well!
將玫瑰圍個圈，一小塊地方充滿了刺
Ring-around the rosie,
a pocket full of spears!
你認為你會是只可愛的狐狸嗎？
Thought you'd be pretty foxy,
didn't you?
她將會是最後一個死的
所以將會目睹其他三人的下場
The last to go will see
the first three go before her.
還有她那骯髒的狗也一樣！
And her mangy little dog too!
來點小火怎樣，稻草人？
How about a little fire, Scarecrow?
救命！我著火了！我著火了！
它燒起來了！
Help! l'm burning! l'm burning!
lt's burning!
別碰那水！
Don't touch that water!
你這可惡的小傢伙！
看看你幹了什麼好事！
You cursed brat!
Look what you've done!
我在融化！融化了！
l'm melting! Melting!
這是什麼樣的世界！這是什麼樣的世界！
What a world! What a world!
誰會想到像你一樣乖巧的小女孩…
Who would've thought
a good little girl like you...
…能夠毀滅我完美的邪惡？
...could destroy
my beautiful wickedness?
注意啊！注意啊！
Look out! Look out!
我要死了
l'm going.
她死了，你已經殺了她
She's dead. You've killed her.
我並不是故意要殺死她
l didn't mean to kill her.
真的，我不是有心的
Really, l didn't.
只不過是他著火了，事情就這樣發生了
lt's just that he was on fire.
向桃樂茜致敬！壞巫婆死了！
Hail to Dorothy!
The Wicked Witch is dead!
致敬！向桃樂茜致敬！
Hail! Hail to Dorothy!
壞巫婆死了！
The Wicked Witch is dead!
這掃帚
The broom.
- 我們能擁有它嗎？
- 請你們拿走它吧
-May we have it?
-Please. And take it with you.
非常謝謝你！
Thank you so much!
現在我們能回去跟大法師說
壞巫婆已經死了
Now we can go tell the Wizard
the Wicked Witch is dead!
壞巫婆死了！
The Wicked Witch is dead!
我能相信我的眼睛嗎？
Can l believe my eyes?
你們帶了什麼回來？
Why have you come back?
請看，先生
我們已經完成了您的吩咐
Please, sir. We've done
what you told us.
我們把壞巫婆的掃帚帶回來給您
We've brought you the broomstick
of the Wicked Witch.
我們還融化了她
We melted her.
你們消滅了她？非常的機智
You liquidated her, eh?
Very resourceful.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
所以我們希望您遵守您對我們的承諾
如果您滿意的話
So we'd like you to keep
your promise to us, if you please.
別急，別急！
Not so fast. Not so fast!
我必須要思考一下這事
l'll have to give the matter
a little thought.
先離開，明天再來
Go away and come back tomorrow.
明天？
Tomorrow?
但是我想馬上回家！
But l want to go home now!
你已經有過充分的時間
You've had plenty of time already.
別激怒偉大又強大的奧茲！
Do not arouse the wrath
of the Great and Powerful Oz!
我說了，明天再來！
l said come back tomorrow!
如果你真的偉大又強大
你應該遵守您的承諾
if you were really great and powerful,
you'd keep your promises.
你在質疑評判偉大的奧茲嗎？
Do you presume to criticize
the Great Oz?
你這忘恩負義的動物！
You ungrateful creatures!
你們要感到幸運
我讓你們明天來謁見我…
Think yourselves lucky that l'm
giving you audience tomorrow...
…而不是20年後！
...instead of 20 years from now!
偉大的奧茲是這麼說的！
The Great Oz has spoken!
別管那個在布簾之後的人
Pay no attention to that man
behind the curtain.
偉大又…奧茲是這麼說的！
The Great and--
Oz has spoken.
你是誰？
Who are you?
好吧，我就是偉大又強大的奧茲大法師
Well, l am the Great and Powerful
Wizard of Oz.
你就是？
You are?
我才不相信你！
l don't believe you!
很不幸這是真的
這裡除了我之外，並沒有其他巫師
l'm afraid it's true.
There's no other Wizard except me.
你這個騙子！
You humbug!
是的，那的確是，我是個騙子
Yes, that's exactly so. l'm a humbug.
你是個很壞的人！
You're a very bad man!
不，親愛的，我是個很好的人
No, my dear. l'm a very good man.
卻是個很差勁的巫師
l'm just a very bad wizard.
那你答應錫人的心怎麼辦？
What about the heart
you promised Tin Man?
還有你答應獅子的的勇氣呢？
And the courage you promised
Cowardly Lion?
還有稻草人的頭腦呢？
And Scarecrow's brain?
噢，每個人都有一顆頭腦
它是再平凡不過的東西
Why, anybody can have a brain.
That's a very mediocre commodity.
每隻卑微的動物，不管是在地上爬的…
Every pusillanimous creature
that crawls on the earth...
…或者潛行於海裡的，都有一顆腦袋
...or slinks through slimy seas
has a brain.
在我原來生活的地方，我們有許多大學…
Back where l come from,
we have universities...
…大量知識存放的地方
人們到那裡學習，以便成為偉大思想家
...seats of great learning,
where men go to become great thinkers.
他們能深入思考哲理
他們並沒有比你更加聰明
They think deep thoughts,
and with no more brains than you have.
但是他們有一樣是你沒有的…
一張文憑
But they have one thing
you haven't got. A diploma.
因此，根據我所被賦予的權力…
Therefore, by virtue
of the authority vested in me...
…得自普魯瑞本士大學董事會…
...by the Universitatus Committeeatum
E Pluribus Unum...
…我在此授與你…
...l hereby confer upon you...
…Th，D，榮譽學位
...the honorary degree of Th.D.
Th，D，是什麼？
Th.D.?
就是「思想學博士」
That's Doctor of Thinkology.
一個等腰三角形兩邊的平方根和…
The sum of the square roots of
two sides of an isosceles triangle...
…等於另一邊的平方根
...is equal to the square root
of the remaining side.
噢，天啊！真令人欣喜！
Oh, joy! Rapture!
我得到我的頭腦了！
l've got a brain!
我要如何才能報答你呢？
How can l thank you enough?
喔，你不需要！
而你，我的好朋友…
Well, you can't.
As for you, my fine friend...
…你是混亂思想的受害者
...you're a victim
of disorganized thinking.
你受困於一種錯覺
認為你面對危險會逃跑是因為…
You are under the delusion
that because you run away from danger...
…你沒有勇氣
你把勇氣與智慧搞混了
...you have no courage.
You're confusing courage with wisdom.
回到我原來生活之處
我們有一種叫做「英雄」的人
Back where l come from,
we have men who are called "heroes."
每年一度，他們會拿出塵封的堅忍勇氣…
Once a year, they take
their fortitude out of mothballs...
…列隊在大街上遊行
...and parade it down the main street.
他們並不比你勇敢
And they have no more courage
than you have.
但是他們有一樣是你沒有的…
一枚勳章
But they have one thing
that you haven't got. A medal.
因此…
Therefore...
…為了你勇敢的帶領
非凡的氣魄…
...for meritorious conduct,
extraordinary valor...
…出色的勇氣
都表現在在對抗壞巫婆時…
...conspicuous bravery
against wicked witches...
…我授與你「三重十字勳章」
...l award you the Triple Cross.
你現在勇氣軍團的一員了
You are now a member
of the Legion of Courage.
啊，各位，我是言語無法形容的
Shucks, folks, l'm speechless.
還有你，我鍍鋅的朋友，你要求顆心
As for you, my galvanized friend,
you want a heart.
你不知道你沒有心是多麼的幸運
You don't know how lucky you are
not to have one.
心一點都不實用
除非它們能被做成牢不可破
Hearts will never be practical
until they can be made unbreakable.
但是我還是想要一顆
But l still want one.
回到我原來生活之處
那裡有人除了行善外，終日無所適事
Back where l come from, there are men
who do nothing all day but good deeds.
他們被稱為愛…
They are called phil--
慈善家，可是他們的情感也沒比你多
Good-deed-doers. And their hearts
are no bigger than yours.
但是他們有一樣你沒有的東西…
一紙褒揚狀
But they have one thing
you haven't got. A testimonial.
因此，在考慮過你的仁慈…
Therefore, in consideration
of your kindness...
…我很榮幸在這裡呈遞給你…
...l take pleasure at this time
in presenting you...
用一件小紀念品
表達我們的尊重及感情
...with a small token
of our esteem and affection.
請記住，我的金屬朋友…
And remember, my sentimental friend...
…愛心並不是以你愛多少人來評估…
...that a heart is not judged
by how much you love...
…而是以有多少人愛你來判定
...but by how much you are loved
by others.
它在滴答響！
lt ticks!
聽著！看啊，它在滴答響！
Listen! Look, it ticks!
讀讀我的獎章怎麼說的…「勇氣」
Read what my medal says. "Courage."
可那不就是事實嗎！
Ain't it the truth!
噢，它們都棒極了
Oh, they're all wonderful.
嘿，那桃樂茜呢？
Hey, what about Dorothy?
是啊，桃樂茜怎麼辦？
Yes, how about Dorothy?
下一個是桃樂茜呀
Dorothy next.
我不認為黑袋子裡有任何能幫我的
l don't think there's anything
in that black bag for me.
你逼我做一個重大的決定
You force me into
a cataclysmic decision.
我必須親自帶桃樂茜回堪薩斯
這是唯一的辦法
The only way to get Dorothy to Kansas
is for me to take her myself.
噢，你會嗎？你可以嗎？
Oh, will you? Could you?
但是操控它你夠靈巧嗎？
But are you clever enough to manage it?
孩子，你傷了我的感情了！
Child, you cut me to the quick!
我可是個老堪薩斯人…
l'm an old Kansas man myself...
…誕生及成長於西部荒野之地…
...born and bred
in the western wilderness...
…奇跡仙境巡迴表演公司的
最傑出之首席氣球駕駛員
...premier balloonist par excellence to
the Miracle Wonderland Carnival Company.
直到有一天在表演同溫層操控技巧…
Until one day, while performing
feats of stratospheric skill...
…文明世界從沒人嘗試過…
...never before attempted
by civilized man...
…一個不幸的現象發生了
...an unfortunate phenomena occurred.
氣球無法順利的回到順風
The balloon failed
to return to the fair.
它發生了？
lt did?
那不會讓你害怕嗎？
Weren't you frightened?
你在談論一個曾當面譏笑死神…
You are talking to a man who has
laughed in the face of death...
…嘲笑厄運和在大災難仍舊大笑的人
我完全嚇呆了
...sneered at doom and chuckled
at catastrophe. l was petrified.
突然間風向變了…
Suddenly the wind changed...
…氣球漂浮下來
進入這高貴的城市…
...and the balloon floated down
into this noble city...
…奧茲的人們立刻擁立我為
首位高級大法師！
...where l was instantly acclaimed Oz,
the first wizard deluxe!
經過他們幾次請求，我接受了工作…
Times being what they were,
l accepted the job...
…留下我的氣球
抗拒立刻逃走的念頭
...retaining my balloon
against the advent of a quick getaway.
而用那氣球，親愛的桃樂茜…
And in that balloon, dear Dorothy...
…你和我將回到那唯一的土地
...you and l will return to
the land of E Pluribus Unum.
我的朋友們，我說，我的朋友們！
My friends. l mean, my friends!
這絕對是前所未有的展示…
This is positively the finest
exhibition ever to be shown...
…盡它所能
...be that as it may.
我，你們的大法師
破 啊丟啦 噎得 噎而踏…
l, your Wizard per ardua ad alta...
…將搭船去從事一次冒險的…
...am about to embark
upon a hazardous...
…和從技術上無法解釋的旅行…
...and technically
unexplainable journey...
…以進入外同溫層！
...into the outer stratosphere!
經過與我的巫師朋友們…
To confer, converse...
…親密的協商討論
...and otherwise hobnob
with my brother wizards.
我在此頒布命令
And l hereby decree
that until what time...
在我回來之前…
...if any, that l return...
…將由有著優越頭腦的稻草人
...the Scarecrow, by virtue
of his highly superior brains...
代替我統治…
...shall rule in my stead...
…並由善良的錫人及勇敢的獅子
...assisted by the Tin Man,
by virtue of his magnificent heart...
從旁協助
...and the Lion,
by virtue of his courage.
像服從我一樣的服從他們
Obey them as you would me.
謝謝你
Thank you.
托托，回來！
Come back!
別丟下我一個人走，我會馬上回來
Don't go without me.
l'll be right back.
攔住那隻狗！
Stop that dog!
這是非常不規則的程序
而且絕對是史無前例的！
This is a highly irregular procedure.
This is absolutely unprecedented!
打開我的出口！
Ruined my exit!
回來！回來！
Come back! Come back!
別丟下我！回來，拜託！
Don't go without me!
Please come back!
我無法回去！我不知道這怎麼操作！
l can't come back!
l don't know how it works!
再見，各位！
Goodbye, folks!
再見！
Goodbye!
現在我再也回不了家了
Now l'll never get home.
留下來跟我們在一起，桃樂茜
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
我們都愛你
We all love you.
我們都不想你離開
We don't want you to go.
你真是體貼…
That's very kind of you...
…但是這裡永遠不會像堪薩斯一樣
...but this could never be like Kansas.
一定要讓艾姆嬸嬸別再擔心
到底我發生什麼事
Auntie Em must have stopped wondering
what happened to me by now.
噢，稻草人，我該怎麼辦？
Oh, Scarecrow, what am l going to do?
看！
Look!
這裡有人能幫助你！
Here's someone who can help you!
你會幫我嗎？你能幫我嗎？
Will you help me? Can you help me?
你再也不需要求助了
You don't need help any longer.
你早就有力量回去堪薩斯了
You've always had the power
to go back to Kansas.
我有？
l have?
你之前為什麼不告訴她？
Why didn't you tell her before?
因為她不會相信我
她必須靠自己學會
Because she wouldn't have believed me.
She had to learn it for herself.
你學到了什麼，桃樂茜？
What have you learned, Dorothy?
我想那是…
l think that it...
…光想見到亨利叔叔和艾姆嬸嬸
是不夠的
...that it wasn't enough just to want
to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
還有如果我未曾
再次尋找我心底的渴望…
And it's that if l ever go looking
for my heart's desire again...
…我將無法看得比我家後院更遠…
...l won't look any further
than my own back yard...
…因為如果它不在我心裡…
...because if it isn't there...
…我從來就沒真的失去過它
...l never really lost it
to begin with.
是這樣嗎？
ls that right?
始終就是那樣
That's all it is.
但是那是如此容易！
我早該幫你想到才對
But that's so easy!
l should've thought of it for you.
我早就應該感覺到它在我心底
l should've felt it in my heart.
她必須自己去發現這件事
She had to find it out for herself.
現在那紅寶石鞋會在兩秒內帶你回家
Now those magic slippers will
take you home in two seconds.
- 托托也是？
- 托托也是
-Toto too?
-Toto too.
- 馬上？
- 任何時間，只要你想要
-Now?
-Whenever you wish.
噢，親愛的
Oh, dear.
那真是美妙得不像真的！
That's too wonderful to be true!
沒想到道別會是這麼困難
lt's gonna be so hard
to say goodbye.
我愛你們所有人
l love you all too.
再見，錫人
Goodbye, Tin Man.
別哭
Don't cry.
你會衒o一塌糊塗的
You'll rust so dreadfully.
拿去，這是你的油壺
Here. Here's your oilcan.
再見
Goodbye.
現在我確定我得到了一顆心了…
Now l know l've got a heart...
…因為它正在破碎了
...because it's breaking.
再見，獅子
Goodbye, Lion.
我知道那是不對的…
l know it isn't right...
…但是我還是會懷念
這一路來你大喊救命的樣子…
...but l'm gonna miss the way
you used to holler for help...
…在你找到你的勇氣之前
...before you found your courage.
如果不是你，我可能永遠找不到它
l would never have found it
if it hadn't been for you.
我想我會最懷念你
l think l'll miss you most of all.
你準備好了沒？
Are you ready now?
說再見，托托
Say goodbye, Toto.
是的，我準備好了
Yes, l'm ready now.
現在閉上你的眼睛…
Then close your eyes...
…並且用你的鞋跟相碰三次…
...and tap your heels
together three times...
…並在內心告訴自己…
...and think to yourself...
…「沒有地方能跟家一樣」
..."There's no place like home.
沒有地方能跟家一樣
There's no place like home."
There's no place like home.
沒有地方能跟家一樣
醒醒，寶貝
Wake up, honey.
桃樂茜，親愛的，是艾姆嬸嬸，親愛的
Dorothy, dear. lt's Aunt Em, darling.
噢，艾姆嬸嬸，真的是你！
Oh, Auntie Em, it's you!
- 是的，親愛的
- 哈囉，您好！有人在家嗎？
-Yes, darling.
-Hello there! Anybody home?
我順道來拜訪，因為我聽說小女孩
被大龍捲風抓走了…
l dropped by because l heard
the little girl got caught in the big--
現在看起來她沒事了
She seems all right now.
她被大力碰撞過
She got quite a bump.
我們還有點擔心她會離我們而去
We kind of thought
she was gonna leave us.
但是我真的離開了你
不過那是件麻煩事兒
But l did leave you.
That's just the trouble.
我試了好多天才能回來
And l tried to get back for days!
哪裡，哪裡，現在乖乖的躺好
There, there, lie quiet now.
你只不過是做了個惡夢
You just had a bad dream.
記得我嗎…
Remember me...
…你的老夥伴，杭克？
...your old pal, Hunk?
還有我…
And me...
…黑克瑞？
...Hickory?
你不會忘了我的臉吧，你會嗎？
You couldn't forget my face,
could you?
但是那不是個夢
But it wasn't a dream.
它是一個真實的地方
lt was a place.
而你，你，你，你…
And you and you and you...
…還有你也在哪裡
...and you were there.
但是你們不可能在那裡的，不是嗎？
But you couldn't have been, could you?
我們夢到許多無聊的事情，當我們…
We dream lots of silly things
when we--
不，艾姆嬸嬸，這是真的
活生生的地方
No, Aunt Em, this was
a real, truly live place.
我還記其中有些不是很好…
And l remember that some of it
wasn't very nice...
…但大部分都很美麗
...but most of it was beautiful.
但是我一直對每個人說同樣的話
「我要回家」
But just the same, all l kept saying
to everybody was, "l want to go home!"
而他們就送我回來了
And they sent me home.
沒有人相信我嗎？
Doesn't anybody believe me?
我們當然相信你，桃樂茜
Of course we believe you, Dorothy.
無論怎樣，托托，我們到家了！
But anyway, Toto, we're home!
家！
Home!
這是我的房間…
And this is my room...
…還有你們全在這裡
...and you're all here.
我將永遠永遠不再離開這裡…
And l'm not going to leave here
ever, ever again...
…因為我愛你們
...because l love you all.
還有，噢，艾姆嬸嬸…
And oh, Auntie Em...
…沒有任何地方能像家一樣！
...there's no place like home!